on a cool October day in 1945
Dr J Robert Oppenheimer
arrived at the White House in Washington DC
a 30 minute meeting had been scheduled with President
Harry S Truman
a meeting that could shape the course of history
that morning Doctor
Robert Oppenheimer
was making an attempt to reason with the president
he had just LED a team of scientists in developing
and testing a weapon
that helped bring about the end of
the Second World War
now he was desperate
to prevent the world from destroying itself
after the atomic bombings of Hiroshima and Nagasaki
Oppenheimer had followed military developments
with deep concern
he felt compelled to personally share his fears
about this devastating
new weapon with the American president
the events of October
1945 marked a turning point in history
but the story began years earlier
with Hitler's invasion of Poland in 1939
which triggered the Second World War
as German forces advanced across Europe
European emigre physicists working in the United States
Learned that their counterparts in Berlin
were experimenting with nuclear fission
fearing its potential as a weapon
they approached Albert Einstein
and persuaded him to collaborate in writing a letter
warning President Franklin D Roosevelt
the letter raised the alarm
that Nazi
Germany might be the first to develop an atomic bomb
in response Roosevelt mobilized US
resources to stay ahead
by executive order
he created the Manhattan Engineer District
placing atomic research
at the center of the American war effort
to lead this unprecedented project
the army appointed General Leslie Groves
a seasoned officer
who had recently overseen construction of the Pentagon
in Washington DC
a significant military achievement
undergrows
the Manhattan Engineer District grew rapidly
employing 75,000 Americans
its structure was compartmentalized
to protect secrecy and maintain focus
Groves knew he needed a brilliant scientist
someone who could lead with vision
rally the nation's top minds
and drive progress at a record pace
after careful consideration
General Groves arrived at his decision
I was completely responsible for the selection of Dr
Oppenheimer
as the head of the Los Alamos Bomb Laboratory
Dr. Oppenheimer
already knew many of the top scientists
and physicists of the era
he had the charisma
intellect and leadership skills
needed to unite them behind a single mission
when Groves and Oppenheimer met for the first time
their top priority was finding a remote location
for a secret laboratory
where the scientists could live and work
around the clock
in complete isolation
Oppenheimer suggested a place in northern New Mexico
where he had spent time with his family
he had hiked the hills
ridden horses through the terrain
and even leased a simple cabin there
he remembered a nearby ranch school set on a Mesa
it seemed ideal
the two men drove out to see it
the old school grounds had solid infrastructure
access to water and room for expansion
Groves turned to Oppenheimer and said this is it
the property was quickly secured for the government
and work began immediately on guardhouses and roads
Oppenheimer started assembling a team of top scientists
engineers and experts from across the country
a laboratory was built and structures began to rise
almost overnight
hundreds of workers and support staff arrived
the guardhouse soon became a hub of activity
scientists came with their families
among them was Oppenheimer's wife Catherine
known as Kitty
who was his confidant and constant companion
Kitty welcomed new arrivals
organized social events
and became the de facto first lady of Los Alamos
as research advanced
military planners
began searching for a nearby location
to test the world's first atomic bomb
the test site needed to be far from populated areas and
inaccessible to the public
a location north of Alamogordo New Mexico was selected
it lay in a desert known as the Jordana del Muertos
Spanish for “journey of the dead”
the area had already been secured by the military
and used for bombing practice
eyewitnesses later recalled that
Oppenheimer played a key role in selecting the site
he reportedly slept under a truck during the search
and seemed more at ease in the desert
than many of his colleagues
over time
a small base camp rose from the barren terrain
Oppenheimer named the site Trinity
several buildings were constructed at the test location
including barracks and a canteen
there was even a pool table for the workers
when the bomb was finally ready for testing
a tall steel tower was built
the idea was to detonate the device above
ground to better observe and measure its effects
by late April 1945
Allied forces had retaken most of Germany
and were closing in on Berlin
Berlin soon fell
and the entire country came under Allied control
German soldiers surrendered
and many members of the Nazi regime were captured
American
intelligence teams recovered a vast trove of secret
military documents
after Germany's surrender
US intelligence agents rushed to the Pina Munda rocket facility
where Werner von Braun
had LED the development of the German V2 rocket
in a nearby cave
American troops discovered 14 tons of technical papers
and hundreds of rocket components
but the agents uncovered an even greater secret
that the Germans under von Proun's supervision
had been developing a rocket intended to strike
New York City
alongside tons of rocket components
technical drawings and documents
the American troops discovered that Dr von brown
and his team of German scientists
were working on the development
of long range weapons that might one day reach
transatlantic targets
this research they realized
could be of great benefit to the US military
the findings were quickly relayed to President Truman
who ordered all materials
and the scientists
to be secured and shipped to the United States
without delay
the US military acted swiftly
transporting the rocket parts and equipment
technical documents
and more than 100 German scientists and their families
including Bernhard von brown
to the United States
the Pentagon decided
the best location for this top secret cargo
was the New Mexico desert
near the atomic test site
almost overnight
New Mexico became the focal point of global attention
it was now home
not only to Los Alamos and the Trinity test site
but also
the centre of a newly planned rocket testing range
although the allies now controlled Germany
and much of Europe
Japan continued to fight fiercely
in the Pacific Theater
in the weeks following Germany's surrender
a conference of Allied leaders was planned
to address Europe's postwar administration
and to coordinate
the final stages of the war against Japan
the meeting was scheduled to begin on July 17
1945 in Potzdam
and later became known as the Potzdam Conference
Truman's secretary of war Henry Stinson
who received daily updates on the Manhattan Project
was aware that the first atomic bomb test was imminent
Stimpson requested
that President Truman
authorise an accelerated timeline for the test
in the desert of New Mexico
so
that its outcome could align with the opening of the
Potsdam Conference
if the test proved successful
Truman could enter the conference
with news of a powerful
new weapon
as leverage for his negotiations with the allies
Truman agreed to the accelerated timeline
and instructed General Groves
to notify the Los Alamos scientists
that the test must occur before the Potsdam meeting
meaning no later than July
Dr Oppenheimer called a meeting at Camp Lodge
in Los Alamos
the scientists agreed that
with full cooperation across all departments
the test could be moved forward
enriched plutonium was prepared in the Los Alamos lab
ahead of the test
under Oppenheimer's supervision
the plutonium was loaded onto military vehicles
it was then driven south through New Mexico
arriving hours later at the Trinity site
340 km away
with great care
the components were assembled at the test site
the plutonium core was inserted into the bomb
nicknamed the gadget
under Oppenheimer's watchful eye
the team completed the final assembly
in the tower above
men were prepared to lift the bomb using hoists
while those below worked the pulleys
the team at the top monitored the process
using mirrors
once the bomb reached the top
the floor was sealed
and technicians wired and inspected the device
to ensure the test could proceed as planned
Oppenheimer notified General Groves
that the test was ready for July 16
Groves relayed the news to President Truman
who was already at the conference in Potsdam
on the morning of the test
light rain and distant lightning threatened a delay
but the skies eventually cleared
at 5 29 a m
on July 1945
the world's first atomic bomb was detonated
in the New Mexico desert
the atomic age had begun
The United States now possessed a weapon capable of
ending the war and compelling Japan to surrender
news of the successful test was sent immediately
to President Truman
in Potsdam via courier telegram
the message read
Doctor has just returned
most enthusiastic and confident
that the little boy is as husky as his big brother
a New York Times reporter
who was part of the official observation group
later described the moment
as if he were present when god created the first light
General Groves recorded in his classified report
that the bomb test was
probably
more important than the discovery of electricity
back at the control room
the scientists reacted with a mix of awe and unease
one of them remarked
we are probably now all sons of bitches
cigarettes and beer were passed around
in subdued Celebration
the explosion had been audible from 160 kilometers away
to avoid public alarm
a press release was issued
claiming that
a munitions depot had accidentally exploded
just hours after the successful test
the USS Indianapolis set sail from San Francisco
heading for the Pacific island of Tinian
on board were components and plutonium
for a second bomb
intended for use against Japan
meanwhile with news of the test in hand
President Truman
showed a noticeable shift in confidence
at Potsdam
as the conference continued
all Allied leaders were briefed on the new weapon
and its likely deployment in the Pacific theater
Truman felt particularly strengthened
in his interactions with Churchill
and Stalin
by the end of the conference
all of the allies had been informed about the new bomb
and its imminent deployment in Japan
I told Stalin
about the atomic explosion
which had been sold off on 16th day of July
down in Alamogordo
New Mexico and
explained to him
that we had the most powerful explosive
that had ever been discovered in the history of the world
and that we expected to use it on Japan
he smiled at me and
bowed and said he was glad we had the explosive
and he hoped that it would end the Japanese war
back in New Mexico Oppenheimer
General Groves
and the scientists visited the blast site
their hard work had paid off
the experiment had worked
Oppenheimer returned to Los Alamos
exhausted but reflective
he began to consider the bomb's next use
should there be a demonstration first
should the Japanese be warned and urged to surrender
what would his colleagues think
now that the theoretical had become real
the sight of the Los Alamos guardhouse
was a welcome relief
he was home at last
soon after returning
Oppenheimer convened a meeting of the scientific team
to address the ethical concerns that had emerged
in the Oak Ridge and Chicago Manhattan Project sites
many scientists signed a petition
urging the president that Japan
should first be given the opportunity to surrender
and that the weapon should
only be used as a last resort
more than 20 years later
Oppenheimer
recalled what he and his colleagues thought at the time
I think that it probably was assumed
it certainly was always assumed at Los Alamos
that if the war
were not over and not clearly
to be brought to a conclusion
by
diplomatic means uh
this weapon would play a part
um
I'm not sure that the men who sat around that room
all had the same
idea of what would happen with the bomb
General Groves blocked the petition
and the scientists effort to reach Truman directly
the president then issued the
the first atomic bomb would be dropped on Japan
by then the Indianapolis had reached Tinian Island
the bomb codenamed Little Boy
was carefully unloaded from the ship
and transported to a hangar
on the Eve of the mission
military technicians rolled the bomb
out to the waiting aircraft
tensions spread among the crew
rumours had circulated
that this was the weapon that could end the war
after several hours of careful preparation
the bomb was loaded into the Boeing B 29 aircraft
just before dawn the Annala Gay took off for Hiroshima
a few hours later
on the morning of Monday August 6 1945
the first atomic bomb ever used in warfare
was dropped on Hiroshima
this is the only known authentic footage
of the explosion
a blast that caused unprecedented devastation
meanwhile the final assembly of the second bomb
Montinian Island was nearing completion
a tactical and operational flight order
detailed the timing
logistics and other elements of the mission
codenamed Fat Man
the bomb was similar in design to the Trinity device
on August it was carefully removed from the hangar
and prepared for the mission
it was first painted with a sealant
then it was armed
and transported to the runway for looting
once again a B29 bomber was carefully prepared
and brought into position
it took off at dawn
on August 1945 the
second atomic bomb was dropped over Nagasaki
the city had been chosen as a secondary target
due to poor weather conditions
the Japanese military could offer
only minimal resistance
within a single month three atomic bombs were detonated
at Alamogordo
Hiroshima
and Nagasaki
the world was forever changed
the overwhelming destruction
LED to the expected surrender of Japan
bringing the Second World War to an end
following the bombings of Hiroshima and Nagasaki
Robert Oppenheimer and his fellow scientists
came under growing scrutiny
facing difficult questions about the ethics
and long term implications of their work
I remember that we first responded
to the question what do scientists think
by saying that they think a variety of things
and this is only natural
uh on the one hand they hoped
this instrument would never be used in war
and therefore
they hoped that we would not
start out by using it
on the other hand they hoped
or other people hoped
that it would put an end to this war
save
countless lives put an end to it
it would have come out
sooner or later in a congressional hearing
if nowhere else
just when we could have dropped the bomb
if we didn't use it
and then
knowing American politics you know as well as I do that
there'd been elections
fought on the basis that every mother whose son
was killed after such and such a date
uh the blood is on the head of the president
the question
was whether we want to save
our people and Japanese as well and win the war
or whether we want to
take a chance on being able to win the war
by killing all our young men
as peace returned
celebrations erupted across the United States
the war was over
and the American public welcomed victory with relief
and pride
Dr Robert Oppenheimer became a household name
for his role in creating the atomic bomb
and helping to end the war
meanwhile
President Truman saw the weapon as a powerful tool
to strengthen his position
both at home and on the global stage
and particularly vis a vis the Soviet Union
with encouragement from his military advisors
he began to pursue a strategy
of expanding US military dominance
through nuclear superiority
the bomb had changed not just warfare
but the direction of American military policy
as the war was shaping up and they were seeing that
with almost certainty
they were going to be able to make these bombs
my grandfather in particular
Neil Bor's influence started turning
their thoughts towards
could this power of these weapons end all war
that's what they started thinking about not
you know are we going to make these bombs
and then control these bombs themselves
but they saw that there was a change in humanity
the way humanity kind of relates to each other
because such powerful technology has been made
that you could end humanity if you have a total war
and that was something that the scientists really
started focusing on
and
that also furthermore there was a way to control that
and the military side
and the government
and the political side was not caught up to that
they were kind of still thinking of
these things like muskets or cannons
we have a weapon
let's make as many weapons as we can
and we'll be more powerful
and that's good
but the scientists
in particular my grandfather
Niels Bohr and some of the other scientists
thought that the significance of
of this particular type of technology
is that we would have to work together
in humanity in a new way
because if we didn't
it would inevitably end in an arms race
and then using the weapons against each other
and destroy everything and it it
turning towards that problem is what he did
while simultaneously finishing his duty
and his work that he had to do
which was fight a war
he was in a war like everybody else
meanwhile General Groves
had received a top secret memo from the US Army
Air Forces headquarters
dated September 1945 the
document laid out plans
to begin immediate mass production of atomic weapons
this was in direct opposition to what Oppenheimer
had hoped for
the memo identified the Soviet Union
as the likely future adversary
an optimum strike the memo continued
would target 66 cities of strategic importance
which would require
204 nuclear bombs
enough to destroy the country
by the fall of 1945
it was clear that the military wanted to
rapidly expand its nuclear arsenal
and this message was passed
directly to President Truman
at the same time
growing discontent was spreading
among many scientists at lost Alamos
who had not expected such escalation
Dr Oppenheimer
who presumably was aware of the memo
and the planned production of
204 atomic bombs
was deeply concerned
scientists at the lab urged him to take action
and deliver their concerns
directly to the secretary of war
and to the president
a recently uncovered memorandum describing a September
1945 meeting reveals the mounting tension
among those who had built the bomb
it noted there is
a distinct opposition on their part
to doing any more work on any bomb
not merely a super bomb but any bomb
Oppenheimer asked George Harrison
assistant to the secretary of war
to arrange a meeting with President Truman
as soon as possible
he still believed that open dialogue between scientists
political leaders
and nations
could help contain the role of nuclear weapons
in future conflicts
when General Groves Learned of the resistance
at Los Alamos
he quickly moved to divide the scientists into two
separate groups
one group would continue with non military research
the other would work on new atomic weapons
to build 204 bombs
the military needed a larger facility
that could operate around the clock
Los Alamos was no longer adequate
plans were drawn up for a new base
near Albuquerque called Sandia
there bomb design and production would continue
storage bunkers were included in the plans
in October 1945
two key military developments took place in New Mexico
the first
was the departure of the 509th Composite Group
the same unit that had dropped the bombs
from Tinian Island
for their new posting at Walker Army Air Base
in Roswell
the base was designed to support B
29 bombers and prepare them for atomic missions
the Annulla Gaye
which had bombed Hiroshima
was part of this transfer
colonel Patrick Henry Sanders
was the assistant base commander
his daughter Susan
still recalls the importance of the Roswell Air Base
the importance of Roswell was it was the only
nuclear strike force base in the world at the time
it was the
the place that
had the nuclear bombs
and was
highly classified
information that was going on between Los Alamos
and Al Magordo
and Fort Bliss and Roswell
the second development
was the arrival of the first German V2 rockets
at the newly established White Sands Proving Grounds
formerly the Alamogordo Bombing and Gunnery Range
where the first atomic bomb had been tested
just two months earlier
a military report by General Hap Arnold
urged the United States to pursue a nuclear
armed rocket program
the German technology was now in American hands
Oppenheimer Learned of both events
and saw the direction military policy was taking
the acceleration of nuclear weapons development
deeply troubled him
he submitted his resignation as director of Los Alamos
news of Oppenheimer's resignation spread quickly
through Los Alamos
General Groves
and the scientific team wanted to honor Oppenheimer
before his departure
a ceremony to Mark the bestowal of the Army
Navy Excellence Award
was the perfect opportunity
Oppenheimer decided the e award ceremony on October
1945 would be his last day at the lab
the event was both a Celebration and a solemn goodbye
in his speech
Oppenheimer
would voice the concerns that weighed heavily on him
General Groves introduced Dr
Oppenheimer to the assembled guests and staff
after receiving his certificate of appreciation
Oppenheimer addressed the gathering
with a short but powerful speech
it is our hope Oppenheimer said
that in years to come
we may look at this scroll
and all that it signifies with pride
today
that pride must be tempered with a profound concern
if atomic bombs are to be added as new weapons
to the arsenals of a warring world
or to the arsenals of nations preparing for war
then the time will come when mankind will curse
the name of Los Alamos
and of Hiroshima
the peoples of this world must unite
or they will perish
his words reflected deep anxiety about the future
his warning moved many of those who listened that day
the Los Alamos community
was shaken by Oppenheimer's departure
his exit only heightened anticipation for the meeting
at the White House
with President Truman
which was set to go forward despite his resignation
Oppenheimer remained convinced that
open communication between scientists
political leaders
and the international community was essential
to limit the threat of nuclear weapons
this was the message
he wanted to give to President Truman
but Truman granted him only a 30 minute meeting
openheimer now a civilian
was entering a political arena
where he held little sway
secretary of Commerce Henry Wallace
who observed his arrival
wrote in his diary
I never saw a man in such a nervous state
as Oppenheimer
he seemed to feel that
the destruction of the human race was imminent
Truman and Oppenheimer
had very different visions
for the future of nuclear weapons
Truman was already moving ahead
with plans to adapt German V2
rocket technology
for atomic delivery
observers said Oppenheimer
appeared as if
he carried the weight of the world on his shoulders
when the meeting began
President Truman asked him
Dr Oppenheimer
when will the Russians develop a nuclear weapon
Oppenheimer replied
Mr President I don't know
Truman raised his voice and said never
then he made a statement
we have spent more than $2 billion
on the greatest scientific gamble in history
and we have won
but the greatest marvel
is not the size of the enterprise
its secrecy or its cost
but the achievement of scientific brains
in making it work
we have made a thing
a most terrible weapon
that has altered abruptly and profoundly
the nature of the world
we have made a thing that
by all the standards of the world we grew up in
is an evil thing
well there's one thing I can say to you
that any schoolboy's hindsights
worth all the presents are a generous foresight
don't you know that
any school boy's afterthoughts worth more than all
a generous forethought
so afterthoughts and things after the fact
have no effect on making a decision
when it's time to make it
at the time
you have to work on what you know at that time
that's what I did and I'm not sorry for it
Oppenheimer looked President Truman in the eye and said
Mr President I feel I have blood on my hands
the remark infuriated Truman who replied
listen the blood is on my hands
you let me worry about that
after the meeting Truman was heard muttering
blood on his hands damn it
he hasn't half as much blood on his hands as I have
you just don't go around bellyaching about it
Truman insisted that nuclear war must be conducted
without tears
he later instructed secretary of State Dean
I don't want to see that son of a bitch
in this office ever again
he didn't set that bomb off I did
in other comments
Truman dismissed Oppenheimer as a crybaby scientist
it was clear
the two men had fundamentally different views
on the meaning and future of nuclear weapons
when Oppenheimer exited the White House
reporters immediately asked him
how the meeting had gone
in the years to come it will be possible to kill
40 million American people
in the 20 largest American towns
by the use of atomic bombs in a single night
I am afraid that the answer to that question is yes
I think the only hope
for our future safety must lie in a collaboration
based on confidence and good faith
with the other peoples of the world
several universities Learned that Dr
Oppenheimer wished to return to academic life
he received numerous offers
including from the California Institute of technology
in Pasadena
Oppenheimer decided not to accept a full time
faculty position
and instead gave lectures
although he now had more time with his family
he realized that his heart was no longer in teaching
he still held a security clearance
and remained involved in national policy
serving
on the board of the Atomic Development Authority
later the Atomic Energy Commission
he continued advocating for the controlled
exchange of nuclear knowledge
the foundation of a global
network of nuclear scientists
and the global limitation of nuclear arms
he spoke publicly
about both the dangers and the hope of the atomic age
often quoting Lincoln's Gettysburg Address
as a statesman he left a lasting impression
he appeared on the covers of Time
Life and other national magazines
and was nominated four times for the Nobel Prize
in physics
during this period
Oppenheimer emerged as a leading public intellectual
regularly consulted on science and policy
by both American and
international figures
in 1947 Oppenheimer was invited by Lewis Strauss
to become the director of the Institute
for Advanced Study
in Princeton New Jersey
this role allowed him to continue his work
with leading scientists
and expand his influence
but
the partnership with Strauss would later prove fateful
and result in the loss of his security clearance
at the urging of Dr Edward Teller
a former colleague from Los Alamos
the US Congress was persuaded
to fund the development of a more powerful
hydrogen bomb
Oppenheimer opposed the project
and appealed to Congress to halt funding
his opposition angered Strauss
who had become chairman of the US
Atomic Energy Commission
alongside President Eisenhower
Strauss championed a more aggressive military posture
in public hearings
Oppenheimer's resistance embarrassed Chairman Strauss
it was the final straw
soon afterwards
Strauss and a small circle in Washington
among them FBI Director
J Edgar Hoover
began circulating false claims that Oppenheimer
was tied to communists
and posed a national security risk
despite objections from local FBI agents
some conversations between Oppenheimer
and his legal team
were secretly recorded
his attorney Lloyd Garrison
was not permitted to know the full list of witnesses
that could be called
at the hearing
on several occasions during the hearing
garrison was asked to leave the room
when classified matters were discussed
a list of more than
40 witnesses was presented
yet no concrete evidence was produced
the hearing became an inquisition aimed not at justice
but at discrediting Oppenheimer
I was completely responsible for the selection of Dr
Oppenheimer
as the head of the Los Alamos bomb laboratory
nothing has happened
during the affair
or afterwards
it LED me to believe that that was not a wise choice
after the decision was made
Strauss called Oppenheimer
to inform him
that his security clearance had been revoked
the response was swift
494 scientists from Los Alamos signed a protest
risking their careers
declassified records
including the full hearing transcripts
confirm that no credible evidence was ever presented
notes from Oppenheimer's longtime secretary
Dorothy Mckibben
showed that on the day the FBI alleged
he met a communist sympathizer
in Berkeley he was actually in New Mexico
Oppenheimer's disillusionment was clear
in the statements he gave after the ruling
what your thoughts are
about what our atomic policy should be
no I I I can't do that I'm not
not close enough to
the facts am I not close enough to the
to the thoughts of those who
are worrying about it
it is very clear that the concept thou shalt not kill
has been complicated in recent years
science has profoundly
altered the conditions of man's life
both materially and in ways of the spirit as well
this extended the range of questions
in which man has a choice
this extended man's freedom
to make significant decisions
no one can predict
what vast new continents of knowledge
the future of science will discover
but we know that
as long as men are free to ask what they will
free to say what they think
free to think what they must
science will never regress
and freedom itself will never be wholly lost
the revocation of his clearance
effectively
ended Oppenheimer's influence in government
and cut him off from the very world
he had helped shape
he later described the security hearing as a farce
though he continued to lecture
he spent increasing time at his secluded retreat
on the island of ST John
in the U s
Virgin Islands
there he built a modest beach house
and spent his days sailing with his wife Kitty
and daughter Tony
despite his isolation international admiration endured
in 1957
France made him an officer of the Legion of honor
your thinking reflects that of Socrates
do you believe that for scientists
what is important is to know oneself
for everybody not just for scientists
do you believe that
scientists are better able to know themselves
through their work
and their discoveries
no no it's a separate thing
in 1963
in an effort to acknowledge the injustice of the past
President John F
Kennedy's advisors proposed awarding Oppenheimer
the Enrico Ferrai Award
Kennedy an admirer
approved the gesture
and set a date for a ceremony at the White House
but just one week before the event
Kennedy was assassinated
his successor President Lyndon B
Johnson presented the award
I think it just possible Mr President
that it has taken some charity
and some courage you to make this award today
despite her grief
Jacqueline Kennedy attended the ceremony
she emphasized how meaningful the award would have been
to her husband
her presence moved Oppenheimer deeply
in 1960 he fulfilled a personal wish by visiting Japan
and seeing first hand
the destruction caused by the atomic bomb
by the end of his life
Oppenheimer
had made peace with his role in shaping the atomic age
in a 1965 interview with The New York Times Magazine
he reflected on that legacy
I never regretted
and do not regret now having done my part of the job
Robert Oppenheimer died of throat cancer on February
his funeral at Princeton was attended by friends
colleagues and dignitaries
his body was cremated
and his ashes were scattered by Kitty
from a small boat
off the coast of their home on ST John
the beach is now referred to as Oppenheimer Beach
during one of his final lectures
he was asked a deeply personal question about his life
will you comment on what contribution if any
Jesus Christ and his gospel
may have
to you or science
I I really wouldn't know about science because
this is a matter
of history which I am sure is very tangled
it is hard to imagine the history of Europe
without Christ
and it's hard to imagine the history of science
without Europe
as for myself I would be
I would be the poorer
I don't know whether I'd be a worse or better scientist
but that's not what you wanted to know
Dr Robert Oppenheimer
had worked relentlessly to help his country
bring an end to a brutal World War
he succeeded only
to be later discredited by the same nation
he had served
his offense
advocating for peace through cooperation
today his message remains as urgent
and relevant as it was in his time
what should we do after the war
what how should we handle this technology that we made
and so the Interim
Scientific
Committee released their report on August 17th, 1945
and it was a written report and had five points
and it was chaired by Robert Oppenheimer
but it was Lawrence Fermi
Compton maybe
like uh it was a group of them
and they worked days and days and days on
on five points and debated them back and forth
and those five points are literally as valid today
as the day they were written
and it said that
these weapons will get more powerful
we'll probably
go into the business of
trying to make a lot more of them
and there is a way to control it
and is only through scientific
openness and cooperation
and these were not kind of radical wild ideas
these guys were in the government
they were on the inside
and they were
the most respected scientists in the world
saying that we can control this technology
and we have to treat it
differently than other military
uses and that wasn't an intuitive idea
and it wasn't resoundly rejected
I mean these are guys created this technology
and they're saying
this is how you handle it
and there was a chance that that advice
could have just directly been taken
the military says what should we do with this
and the government
and they could've listened to the scientists
and managed it
the way they proposed from that very beginning
uh period and when I look back on history
I think it's worth talking over that period
and all the way through 1947
over and over and
over again and have people understand
how close and how clear it was to the scientists
how we should manage this technology
and how like effectively just arbitrary
bureaucratic decisions
did the exact opposite of what they
advised and went into an arms race
and almost destroyed the world
it's not like they thought their path out
they they did think their path out
they said I disagree with you scientists
you don't know what you're talking about
we'll do it our way
and we had 70 years to test it
and it turns out the scientists were 100% right
except for blowing ourselves up
which to this day is an open question
we could all die
so that was a really interesting period
that they wrote down
provided this advice
tried to deliver it
and it didn't get there
1945年10月一个凉爽的日子
罗伯特·奥本海默博士
抵达华盛顿特区的白宫
与总统安排了30分钟的会议
哈里·S·杜鲁门
一次可能改变历史进程的会议
那天早上医生
罗伯特·奥本海默
试图和总统讲道理
他刚刚带领一个科学家团队开发
并测试武器
这有助于结束
第二次世界大战
现在他绝望了
防止世界自我毁灭
在广岛和长崎原子弹爆炸后
奥本海默一直关注着军事发展
深切关注
他觉得有必要亲自分享他的恐惧
关于这个毁灭性的
美国总统的新武器
十月事件
1945年标志着历史的转折点
但故事开始于几年前
1939年希特勒入侵波兰
引发了第二次世界大战
随着德国军队在欧洲的推进
在美国工作的欧洲移民物理学家
得知他们在柏林的同行
正在进行核裂变实验
担心它作为武器的潜力
他们接近阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦
并说服他合作写信
警告富兰克林·罗斯福总统
这封信敲响了警钟
那个纳粹
德国可能是第一个研制原子弹的国家
作为回应，罗斯福动员美国
保持领先的资源
根据行政命令
他创建了曼哈顿工程师区
放置原子研究
在美国战争的中心
领导这个前所未有的项目
军队任命莱斯利·格罗夫斯将军
经验丰富的军官
他最近监督了五角大楼的建设
在华盛顿特区
重大军事成就
矮生
曼哈顿工程师区发展迅速
雇佣了75000名美国人
它的结构被分隔开来
为了保密和保持焦点
Groves知道他需要一位杰出的科学家
一个有远见的人
集结全国顶尖人才
并以创纪录的速度推动进展
经过深思熟虑
Groves将军做出了决定
我完全负责选择博士
奥本海默
作为洛斯阿拉莫斯炸弹实验室的负责人
奥本海默博士
已经认识了许多顶尖的科学家
和那个时代的物理学家
他很有魅力
智力和领导能力
需要团结他们完成一项任务
当格罗夫斯和奥本海默第一次见面时
他们的首要任务是找到一个偏远的地方
为了一个秘密实验室
科学家可以在那里生活和工作
昼夜不停
完全孤立
奥本海默建议在新墨西哥州北部找个地方
他和家人在一起的地方
他爬山
骑马穿越地形
甚至在那里租了一个简单的小屋
他记得附近的一所农场学校坐落在梅萨
看起来很理想
那两个人开车出去看
老校区有坚实的基础设施
获得水和扩张空间
格罗夫斯转向奥本海默说这就是了
政府很快就得到了财产
警卫室和道路的工作立即开始
奥本海默开始组建一个由顶尖科学家组成的团队
来自全国各地的工程师和专家
建造了一个实验室，建筑物开始出现
几乎一夜之间
数百名工人和支持人员到达
警卫室很快成为活动中心
科学家们和他们的家人一起来的
其中包括奥本海默的妻子凯瑟琳
被称为Kitty
是他的知己和永远的伴侣
Kitty欢迎新来的
有组织的社交活动
成为洛斯阿拉莫斯事实上的第一夫人
随着研究的进展
军事规划者
开始寻找附近的地点
测试世界上第一颗原子弹
试验场需要远离人口稠密地区
公众无法访问
新墨西哥州阿拉莫戈多以北的一个地点被选中
它坐落在被称为乔丹娜·德尔·穆尔托斯的沙漠中
西班牙语为“死亡之旅”
这个地区已经被军方控制住了
并用于轰炸演习
目击者后来回忆说
奥本海默在选址中起了关键作用
据报道，在搜查过程中他睡在卡车下面
在沙漠中似乎比他的许多同事都
更自在
随着时间的推移
一个小小的大本营从贫瘠的地形上拔地而起
奥本海默将该地点命名为三一
在测试地点建造了几栋建筑
包括兵营和食堂
甚至还为工人们准备了台球桌
当炸弹终于准备好进行测试时
建造了一座高大的钢塔
想法是引爆上面的装置
研磨以更好地观察和测量其效果
到1945年4月下旬
盟军已经夺回了德国的大部分地区
正在逼近柏林
柏林很快沦陷
整个国家都在盟军的控制之下
德国士兵投降了
和许多纳粹政权成员被俘
美国
情报小组发现了大量秘密
军事文件
德国投降后
美国情报人员赶到皮纳蒙达火箭设施
沃纳·冯·布劳恩
领导了德国V2火箭的开发
在附近的山洞里
美军发现了14吨的技术文件
和数百个火箭部件
但特工们发现了一个更大的秘密
德国在冯·普劳恩的监督下
一直在开发一种旨在打击
纽约市的火箭
还有数吨火箭部件
技术图纸和文件
美军发现冯·布朗博士
和他的德国科学家团队
正在开发中
有朝一日可能达到的远程武器
跨大西洋目标
他们实现的这项研究
可能对美军大有裨益
调查结果很快被传达给了杜鲁门总统
订购了所有材料
和科学家们
被保护并运到美国
刻不容缓
美军迅速采取行动
运送火箭零件和设备
技术文件
100多名德国科学家和他们的家人
包括伯恩哈德·冯·布朗
去美国
五角大楼决定
这批绝密货物的最佳位置
是新墨西哥沙漠
在原子试验场附近
几乎一夜之间
新墨西哥州成为全球关注的焦点
它现在回家了
不仅是洛斯阿拉莫斯和三一试验场
但也
新计划的火箭试验场的中心
虽然盟军现在控制了德国
和欧洲大部分地区
日本继续进行激烈的战斗
在太平洋战场
在德国投降后的几周内
计划召开一次盟军领导人会议
向欧洲战后政府发表讲话
并协调
抗日战争的最后阶段
会议原定于7月17日开始
1945年在波茨坦
后来被称为波茨坦会议
杜鲁门的战争部长亨利·斯丁森
收到了曼哈顿计划的每日更新
意识到第一次原子弹试验迫在眉睫
史汀生要求
杜鲁门总统
授权加快测试时间表
在新墨西哥州的沙漠里
所以
其结果可以与
波茨坦会议
如果测试证明成功
杜鲁门可以参加会议
有一个强大的消息
新武器
作为他与盟军谈判的筹码
杜鲁门同意加速时间表
并指示Groves将军
通知洛斯阿拉莫斯的科学家
测试必须在波茨坦会议之前进行
不迟于七月
奥本海默博士在营地小屋召集了一个会议
在洛斯阿拉莫斯
科学家们一致认为
与所有部门通力合作
测试可以提前
浓缩钚是在洛斯阿拉莫斯实验室制备的
领先于测试
在奥本海默的监督下
钚被装载到军用车辆上
然后它被向南穿过新墨西哥州
几小时后到达三一现场
340公里以外
小心翼翼
组件在测试现场组装
钚核被插入炸弹
绰号小玩意
在奥本海默的监视下
团队完成了最终组装
在上面的塔里
人们准备用起重机举起炸弹
而下面的人在滑轮上工作
最高层的团队监控了这个过程
使用镜子
一旦炸弹到达顶部
地板是密封的
技术人员接线并检查了设备
以确保测试能按计划进行
奥本海默通知了格罗夫斯将军
7月16日的测试已经准备好了
格罗夫斯把消息转达给了杜鲁门总统
他已经参加了波茨坦的会议
在测试的早上
小雨和远处的闪电威胁要延迟
但天空最终还是放晴了
早上5点29分
1945年7月
世界上第一颗原子弹被引爆
在新墨西哥沙漠
原子时代开始了
美国现在拥有一种能够
结束战争迫使日本投降
测试成功的消息立即发送
杜鲁门总统
在波茨坦通过快递电报
消息称
医生刚刚回来
对代号为“小男孩”的原子弹的首次成功引爆感到非常激动
并确信其威力与之前代号为“大胖子”的测试装置一样强劲。
纽约时报记者
他是官方观察小组的一员
后来描述了那一刻
仿佛上帝创造第一道光时他就在场
Groves将军在他的机密报告中
炸弹测试是
大概
比电的发现更重要
回到控制室
科学家们的反应是既敬畏又不安
其中一个说
我们现在大概都是混蛋
香烟和啤酒四处传播
在压抑的庆典中
160公里外都能听到爆炸声
避免公众恐慌
发布了新闻稿
声称
一个弹药库意外爆炸了
测试成功几个小时后
印第安纳波利斯号从旧金山启航
前往太平洋的提尼安岛
船上有部件和钚
准备第二个炸弹
用于对付日本
与此同时，已知测试消息
杜鲁门总统
显示出明显的信心转变
在波茨坦
随着会议的继续
所有盟军领导人都被告知了这种新武器
以及它可能在太平洋战区的部署
杜鲁门感到特别强大
在他与丘吉尔的互动中
和斯大林
在会议结束时
所有盟国都被告知了新炸弹的事
以及它即将在日本的部署
我告诉斯大林
关于原子弹爆炸
已于7月16日在新墨西哥州
和阿拉莫戈多
测试，并且
向他解释
我们有在世界历史上曾被发现的
最强大的炸药
我们希望在日本使用它
他对我微笑
鞠躬说他很高兴我们有炸药
他希望这能结束日本战争
回到新墨西哥州奥本海默
格罗夫斯将军
科学家们参观了爆炸现场
他们的辛勤工作得到了回报
实验奏效了
奥本海默回到了洛斯阿拉莫斯
精疲力竭但深思熟虑
他开始考虑炸弹的下一步用途
应该先有预告吗？
是否应该警告日本人并敦促他们投降
他的同事会怎么想
既然理论变成了现实
洛斯阿拉莫斯警卫室的景象
是一种可喜的解脱
他终于回家了
回来后不久
奥本海默召集了一次科学小组会议
来解决已经出现的伦理问题
在橡树岭和芝加哥曼哈顿项目现场
许多科学家签署了一份请愿书
敦促总统让日本
应该首先得到投降的机会
武器应该
只能作为最后手段使用
20多年后
奥本海默
回忆起他和他的同事当时的想法
我想这可能是假设
在洛斯阿拉莫斯，人们当然一直认为
如果战争
没有结束，也不清楚能否
得出结论
由
外交手段
这个武器会起作用
嗯
我不确定坐在那个房间里的人
都一样
知道炸弹会发生什么
Groves将军阻止了请愿
科学家们试图直接联系杜鲁门
总统随后发布了
第一颗原子弹将投在日本
那时印第安纳波利斯号已经到达天宁岛
代号为小男孩的炸弹
被小心地从船上卸下
并被运送到机库
任务前夕
军事技术人员滚动炸弹
去等候的飞机
紧张局势在船员中蔓延
谣言四起
这是可以结束战争的武器
经过几个小时的精心准备
炸弹被装入波音B 29飞机
黎明前，安娜拉·盖伊号飞往广岛
几个小时后
1945年8月6日星期一早上
第一颗用于战争的原子弹
被空投到广岛
这是唯一已知的真实录像
爆炸
造成空前破坏的爆炸
与此同时，第二枚炸弹的最终组装
蒙蒂尼安岛接近完工
战术和作战飞行命令
详细说明时间
特派团的后勤和其他部门
代号胖子
炸弹的设计与三一装置相似
八月，它被小心翼翼地从机库中取出
并为任务做好准备
它首先被涂上密封剂
然后它被武装起来了
运到跑道上
一架B29轰炸机再次被精心准备
并就位
它在黎明时起飞了
1945年8月
第二颗原子弹在长崎上空投下
这座城市被选为第二目标
由于恶劣的天气条件
日本军方可以提供
只有最小的阻力
在一个月内引爆了三颗原子弹
在阿拉莫戈多
广岛
和长崎
世界永远改变了
压倒性的破坏
导致日本投降
结束第二次世界大战
在广岛和长崎爆炸事件之后
罗伯特·奥本海默和他的科学家同事们
受到越来越多的审查
面对关于道德的难题
以及他们工作的长期影响
我记得我们第一次回应
科学家们是怎么想的
说他们想各种各样的事情
这是很自然的
呃一方面他们希望
这种工具永远不会在战争中使用
因此
他们希望我们不要
从使用它开始
另一方面他们希望
或者其他人希望
它会结束这场战争
保留
无数的生命去结束了它
它会出来的
迟早在国会听证会上
如果没有别的地方
就在我们可以投下炸弹的时候
如果我们不使用它
然后
你和我一样了解美国政治
有过选举
斗争的基础是每个儿子的母亲
在某次约会后被杀
呃总统头上有血
问题
是我们是否想拯救
我们的人民和日本人，赢得战争
或者我们是否愿意
冒险赢得战争
杀死我们所有的年轻人
随着和平的回归
美国各地爆发了庆祝活动
战争结束了
美国公众如释重负地欢迎胜利
和骄傲
罗伯特·奥本海默博士成了家喻户晓的名字
因为他在制造原子弹中的重大作用
帮助结束战争
同时
杜鲁门总统认为这种武器是一种强大的工具
来巩固他的地位
无论是在国内还是在全球舞台上
尤其是对苏联
在军事顾问的鼓励下
他开始追求一种策略
扩大美国的军事优势
通过核优势
炸弹不仅改变了战争
但是美国军事政策的方向
随着战争的发展，他们看到了这一点
几乎可以肯定
他们将能够制造这些炸弹
尤其是我的祖父
尼尔·博尔的影响力开始转向
他们的想法
这些武器的威力能结束所有战争吗？
这就是他们开始考虑的不是
你知道我们要制造这些炸弹吗？
然后自己控制这些炸弹
但是他们看到了人性的改变
人类相互联系的方式
因为已经制造出如此强大的技术
如果你有一场全面战争，你就可以终结人类
这是科学家们真正
开始专注于
和
此外，还有一种方法可以控制它
和军事方面
和政府
政治方面没有跟上这一点
他们还在想
这些东西像火枪或大炮
我们有武器
让我们制造尽可能多的武器
我们会变得更强大
这很好。
但是科学家们
尤其是我的祖父
尼尔斯·玻尔和其他一些科学家
认为的意义
这种特殊类型的技术
我们必须一起工作
以一种新的方式在人性中
因为如果我们不这样做
它将不可避免地以军备竞赛告终
然后用武器互相攻击
并摧毁一切
转向那个问题就是他所做的
同时完成他的任务
和他必须做的工作
那就是打仗
他和其他人一样在打仗
同时格罗夫斯将军
收到了美国陆军的绝密备忘录
空军司令部
1945年9月
文件列出的计划
立即开始大规模生产核武器
这与奥本海默
曾希望的背道而驰
备忘录确定了苏联
作为未来可能的对手
备忘录继续进行最佳打击
将针对66个具有战略重要性的城市
这将需要
204枚核弹
足以摧毁这个国家
到1945年秋天
很明显军方想要
迅速扩大其核武库
这条消息被传递了
直接给杜鲁门总统
同时
日益增长的不满正在蔓延
在失落的阿拉莫斯的许多科学家中
谁没有预料到这种升级
奥本海默博士
大概知道备忘录的人
和计划生产
204颗原子弹
深切关注
实验室的科学家敦促他采取行动
并表达他们的担忧
直接交给战争部长
还有总统
最近发现的一份备忘录描述了一个九月
1945年的会议揭示了日益紧张的局势
在制造炸弹的人当中
它注意到有
他们明显反对
在任何炸弹上做更多的工作
不仅仅是超级炸弹而是任何炸弹
奥本海默问乔治·哈里森
陆军部长助理
安排与杜鲁门总统会面
尽快
他仍然相信科学家之间的公开对话
政治领导人
和国家
可能有助于遏制核武器的作用
在未来的冲突中
当Groves将军得知抵抗时
在洛斯阿拉莫斯
他迅速采取行动将科学家一分为二
独立组
一组将继续进行非军事研究
另一个会研究新的原子武器
制造204枚炸弹
军方需要更大的设施
可以全天候运行
洛斯阿拉莫斯已经不够用了
计划建立一个新基地
在阿尔伯克基附近叫桑迪亚
那里的炸弹设计和生产将继续
计划中包括储存掩体
1945年10月
新墨西哥州发生了两起重大军事事件
第一
是第509合成集团的离开
扔炸弹的同一支部队
来自天宁岛
他们在沃克陆军空军基地的新职位
在罗斯威尔
底座设计用于支持B
29架轰炸机，为原子任务做准备
环带盖伊
轰炸了广岛
是这次转移的一部分
帕特里克·亨利·桑德斯上校
是助理基地指挥官
他的女儿苏珊
仍然记得罗斯威尔空军基地的重要性
罗斯威尔的重要性在于它是唯一
当时世界上的核打击力量基地
这是
那个地方
拥有核弹
并且是
高度机密
洛斯阿拉莫斯之间发生的信息
和Al Magordo
还有布利斯堡和罗斯威尔
第二发展
是第一批德国V2火箭的到来
在新成立的白沙试验场
以前是阿拉莫戈多轰炸和射击靶场
在那里测试了第一颗原子弹
就在两个月前
哈普将军的军事报告Arnold
敦促美国追求核
武装火箭计划
德国的技术现在掌握在美国人手中
奥本海默得知了这两件事
看到了军事政策的发展方向
核武器发展的加速
深深困扰着他
他递交辞呈辞去洛斯阿拉莫斯董事的职务
奥本海默辞职的消息迅速传开
穿过洛斯阿拉莫斯
格罗夫斯将军
科学团队想向奥本海默致敬
在他离开之前
纪念军队赐予的仪式
海军卓越奖
是个绝佳的机会
奥本海默决定在十月举行e颁奖典礼
1945年是他在实验室的最后一天
这件事既是庆祝又是庄严的告别
在他的演讲中
奥本海默
会表达他沉重的担忧
格罗夫斯将军介绍了
奥本海默致聚集在一起的来宾和工作人员
收到他的感谢状后
奥本海默在集会上致辞
简短而有力的演讲
这是我们的希望奥本海默说
在未来的几年里
我们可以看看这个卷轴
以及它所象征的骄傲
今天
这种骄傲必须带着深切的关心
如果要增加原子弹作为新武器
交战世界的军火库
或者准备战争的国家的武器库
那么人类诅咒的时候就会到来
洛斯阿拉莫斯的名字
和广岛
全世界人民必须团结起来
否则他们会灭亡
他的话反映了对未来的深切忧虑
他的警告感动了许多那天听的人
洛斯阿拉莫斯社区
被奥本海默的离开所动摇
他的离开只是增加了对会议的期待
在白宫
杜鲁门总统
尽管他辞职了，但该计划仍将继续
奥本海默仍然坚信
科学家之间的公开交流
政治领导人
国际社会是必不可少的
限制核武器的威胁
这是消息
他想送给杜鲁门总统
但杜鲁门只同意了他30分钟的会面
Openhemer现在是平民了
正在进入政治舞台
在那里他几乎没有影响力
商务部长亨利·华莱士
谁观察了他的到来
写在他的日记里
我从未见过如此紧张的人
作为奥本海默
他似乎感觉到了
人类的毁灭迫在眉睫
杜鲁门和奥本海默
有非常不同的愿景
为了核武器的未来
杜鲁门已经开始行动了
计划改编德国V2
火箭技术
用于原子交付
观察家说奥本海默
好像
他把世界的重担扛在肩上
会议开始时
杜鲁门总统要求他
奥本海默博士
俄国人什么时候会研制出核武器
奥本海默回答说
总统先生我不知道
杜鲁门提高嗓门说绝不
然后他发表了声明
我们已经花了20亿多美元
历史上最大的科学赌博
我们赢了
但最伟大的奇迹
不是企业的规模
它的秘密或它的成本
但是科学大脑的成就
让它工作
我们做了一件事
最可怕的武器
突然而深刻地改变了
世界的本质
我们做了一件事
以我们成长的世界的所有标准来看
是一件邪恶的事情
好吧，有一件事我可以对你说
任何学生的后见之明
值得所有的是慷慨的远见
你不知道吗？
任何学生的事后想法都比一切都重要
先见之明
所以事后的想法和事情
对做决定没有影响
当该做的时候
当时
你必须在你当时知道的事情上努力
这就是我所做的，我并不为此感到抱歉
奥本海默看着杜鲁门总统的眼睛说
总统先生我觉得我双手沾满鲜血
这句话激怒了杜鲁门，他回答说
听着我双手沾满鲜血
你让我担心这个
会后杜鲁门被听到喃喃自语
他双手沾满鲜血该死的
他手上沾的血还没我的一半多
你只是不要到处抱怨
杜鲁门坚持必须进行核战争
无泪
他后来指示国务卿迪恩
我不想看到那个狗娘养的
在这个办公室里
不是他放的炸弹是我放的
在其他评论中
杜鲁门把奥本海默斥为爱哭的科学家
很明显
这两个人有根本不同的观点
核武器的意义和未来
当奥本海默离开白宫时
记者立即问他
会议进展如何
在未来的几年里，有可能杀死
4000万美国人民
在美国最大的20个城镇
在一夜之间使用原子弹
恐怕这个问题的答案是肯定的
我认为唯一的希望
为了我们未来的安全必须依靠合作
基于信心和诚意
与世界其他民族
几所大学了解到
奥本海默希望回归学术生活
他收到了许多邀请
包括加州理工学院的
在帕萨迪纳
奥本海默决定不接受全职
教职
而是讲课
虽然他现在有更多的时间和家人在一起
他意识到他的心已经不在教学上了
他仍然持有安全许可
并继续参与国家政策
发球
在原子能发展局董事会
后来原子能委员会
他继续主张控制
核知识交流
全球的基础
核科学家网络
以及核武器的全球限制
他公开讲话
关于原子时代的危险和希望
经常引用林肯的葛底斯堡演说
作为一个政治家他给人留下了深刻的印象
他上了时代周刊的封面
生活和其他全国性杂志
四次被提名诺贝尔奖
在物理学中
在此期间
奥本海默成为一位杰出的公共知识分子
定期就科学和政策进行咨询
由美国和
国际人物
1947年，刘易斯·施特劳斯邀请奥本海默
成为研究所的主任
高级学习
在新泽西州的普林斯顿
这个角色使他能够继续他的工作
与领先的科学家
扩大他的影响力
但是
与施特劳斯的合作后来证明是决定性的
并导致他失去安全权限
在Edward Teller博士的敦促下
来自洛斯阿拉莫斯的前同事
美国国会被说服
资助开发更强大的
氢弹
奥本海默反对这个项目
并呼吁国会停止拨款
他的反对激怒了施特劳斯
他已经成为美国的主席
原子能委员会
和艾森豪威尔总统一起
施特劳斯主张更具侵略性的军事姿态
在公开听证会上
奥本海默的反抗让施特劳斯主席很尴尬
这是最后一根稻草
不久之后
施特劳斯和华盛顿的一个小圈子
其中有联邦调查局局长
J·埃德加·胡佛
开始散布关于奥本海默
和共产党有联系
并构成国家安全风险
尽管当地FBI探员反对
奥本海默之间的一些对话
和他的法律团队
被秘密记录
他的律师劳埃德·加里森
不允许知道证人的完整名单
那可以叫做
在听证会上
在听证会期间多次
Garrison被要求离开房间
在讨论机密问题时
一个以上的列表
有40名证人出庭作证
但没有提供具体证据
听证会变成了一场不旨在伸张正义的宗教裁判所
而是抹黑奥本海默
我完全负责选择博士
奥本海默
作为洛斯阿拉莫斯炸弹实验室的负责人
什么都没发生
在婚外情期间
或之后
这让我相信这不是一个明智的选择
做出决定后
施特劳斯打电话给奥本海默
通知他
他的安全许可被撤销了
反应迅速
来自洛斯阿拉莫斯的494名科学家签署了一份抗议
拿自己的事业冒险
解密记录
包括完整的听证会记录
确认从未提供过可信的证据
奥本海默长期秘书的笔记
多萝西·麦基本
显示在联邦调查局声称的那天
他遇到了一个共产主义同情者
在伯克利，他实际上在新墨西哥州。
奥本海默的幻灭很明显
在他裁决后的陈述中
你的想法是什么
我们的原子政策应该是什么
不，我不能这么做，我没有。
不够接近
事实是我不够接近
那些人的想法
正在担心它
很明显，你不能扼杀这个概念
近年来变得复杂了
科学已经深刻地
改变了人类的生活条件
无论是物质上还是精神上
这扩大了问题的范围
其中人类有选择
这个人的自由
做出重大决定
没人能预测
多么广阔的知识新大陆
科学的未来将发现
但我们知道
只要男人可以自由地问他们会问什么
自由说出他们的想法
自由思考他们必须做的
科学永远不会倒退
自由本身永远不会完全失去
撤销他的许可
有效地
终结了奥本海默对政府的影响
并将他与这个世界隔绝
他帮助塑造了
他后来将安全听证会描述为一场闹剧
尽管他继续讲课
他花越来越多的时间在隐居处
在圣约翰岛上
在美国
维尔京群岛
在那里他建造了一座朴素的海滨别墅
整天和妻子Kitty一起出海
和女儿托尼
尽管他与世隔绝，但国际钦佩依然存在
在1957年
法国任命他为荣誉军团军官
你的思想反映了苏格拉底的思想
你相信对于科学家来说
重要的是认识自己
对每个人来说，不仅仅是对科学家
你相信吗？
科学家能够更好地了解自己
通过他们的工作
以及他们的发现
不，不，这是另一回事。
1963年
为了承认过去的不公正
约翰·F.总统
肯尼迪的顾问们提议授予奥本海默
Enrico Ferrai奖
肯尼迪是个崇拜者
批准了这个手势
并确定在白宫举行仪式的日期
但就在活动前一周
肯尼迪是被暗杀的
他的继任者总统Lyndon B
约翰逊颁奖
我想有可能总统先生
这需要一些慈善机构
以及你今天能获奖的勇气
尽管她很悲伤
杰奎琳·肯尼迪出席了仪式
她强调了该奖项的意义
给她丈夫
她的出现深深打动了奥本海默
1960年他实现了个人愿望访问了日本
并亲眼目睹
原子弹造成的破坏
在他生命的尽头
奥本海默
已经接受了他在塑造原子时代中的角色
在1965年接受《纽约时报》杂志采访时
他反思了那份遗产
我从未后悔过
不要后悔现在已经完成了我的工作
罗伯特·奥本海默于2月死于喉癌
他在普林斯顿的葬礼有朋友参加
同事和政要
他的尸体被火化了
他的骨灰被Kitty撒了
从一艘小船上
在圣约翰他们家的海岸
海滩现在被称为奥本海默海滩
在他最后一次演讲中
他被问到一个关于他生活的非常私人的问题
如果有的话，你会评论什么贡献吗？
耶稣基督和他的福音
可能有
对你或科学
我真的不太懂科学因为
这是一件事
我相信这是非常复杂的
很难想象欧洲的历史
没有基督
很难想象科学史
没有欧洲
至于我自己，我会
我会更穷
我不知道我能成为一个更好还是更坏的科学家
但那不是你想知道的
罗伯特·奥本海默博士
不遗余力地帮助他的国家
结束残酷的世界大战
他只成功了
后来被同一个国家抹黑
他服过役
他的进攻
以合作促和平
今天他的信息仍然很紧急
和他那个时代一样重要
战后我们该怎么办
我们应该如何处理我们创造的这项技术？
所以过渡时期
科学的
委员会于1945年8月17日发布了他们的报告
这是一份书面报告，有五分。
会议由罗伯特·奥本海默主持
但那是劳伦斯·费米
也许是康普顿
就像呃是他们一群人
他们日复一日地工作
在五点上反复辩论
这五点在今天同样有效
就像他们写的那天一样
它说
这些武器会变得更强大
我们可能会
从事
试图制造更多的它们
而且有办法控制它
只有通过科学
开放合作
这些并不是什么激进疯狂的想法。
这些人是政府官员
他们在里面
他们是
世界上最受尊敬的科学家
说我们可以控制这项技术
我们必须治疗它
不同于其他军队
使用，这不是一个直观的想法
它没有被强烈拒绝
我是说，这些人创造了这项技术。
他们说
你就是这样处理的
这个建议有可能
可能直接被带走了
军方说我们该怎么处理这个
和政府
他们本可以听科学家的话
并管理它
他们从一开始就求婚的方式
呃，当我回顾历史时
我认为这段时间值得讨论
直到1947年
一遍又一遍
一遍又一遍，让人们理解
对科学家来说有多接近，有多清楚
我们应该如何管理这项技术
以及如何有效地只是任意的
官僚决策
做了与他们完全相反的事情
建议并进入军备竞赛
几乎毁灭了世界
他们并不认为自己的出路
他们确实认为他们的出路
他们说我不同意你们科学家的观点
你不知道你在说什么
我们按自己的方式来
我们有70年的时间来测试它
事实证明科学家们是100%正确的
除了把我们自己炸飞
这至今仍是个悬而未决的问题
我们可能都会死
那真是个有趣的时期。
他们写下的
提供了这个建议
试图交付它
它没有到达那里。